# Christopher M. Hannon, PhD

CONTACT Information Christopher Hannon Chicago, IL Cell: (630) 286-1551 E-mail: chris@nomadic-code.net

(open to relocation)

https://www.linkedin.com/in/annonch

Professional Summary Outcome driven Software Engineer with over 10 years of experience in Information Technology. Confident in ability to increase quality and efficiency of software delivery by improving throughput and stability. Track record of creating tools and processes to reduce organizational cost and tech debt. Committed to team development, continuous learning, and contributing to team success.

Areas of Expertise • Software Engineering

• CI/CD

• Site Reliability (SRE)

• Continuous Delivery

• Google Cloud Platform

• Cybersecurity

• Test Driven Development

• Kubernetes

• Product Management

Professional Experience

### Ford Motor Company, Remote

Software Engineering Manager, Platform Engineering

June, 2021 - Present

Led the Platform Enablement team in the newly formed Ford Pro business unit. Responsibilities included leading DevSecOps, Google Cloud Platform, and Site Reliability Engineering teams and supporting the software development lifecycle

- $\bullet$  Led the design of a CI/CD framework in Tekton reducing pipeline execution time by 50%, and improving deployment frequency by 20%
- Created terraform and pipeline templates reducing time to market for over 100 microservices saving Ford Pro Tech \$8M and establishing standardization and GCP reference frameworks
- Led the establishment of the Ford Pro Observability Platform using OpenTelemetry and Datadog to send application Logs, Metrics, Traces and establish SLOs and Monitors
- Established Golden Container Image processes and tools reducing risk and improving security
- Collaborated with US and India teams providing Platform Enablement to 400+ engineers

#### CRCL GmbH, Remote

Software Engineer

Jan 2020 - June 2021

Led the DevSecOps strategy and implementation for a 9 person Platform as a Service startup.

- Led the migration of platform hosting from Docker Swarm to Kubernetes on EC2 AWS
- Build and deployed cluster deployment tools reducing time to deploy from 1 day to 1 hour
- Established Observability Platform using Prometheus and Grafana

## Los Alamos National Laboratory, Los Alamos, New Mexico

 $Graduate\ Research\ Assistant$ 

May 2017 - May 2020

- Designed and implemented machine learning models to identify anomalies in multivariate realtime streaming data
- Established Parallel Discrete Event Simuation Benchmark representing commonly ran HPC jobs
- Implemented optimistic mode for the HPC Simian Parallel Discrete Simulation engine in Python

#### Computer Science Department, Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, IL

Research Assistant

2013 - May 2020

- First author on 8 conference papers, 4 journal articles, and 1 book chapter
- Led office hours, present lectures, and create course materials

**EDUCATION** 

Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, Illinois USA

• Ph.D., Computer Science, May 2020

• B.S., Computer Science, May 2015